- Why is this happening? - [don't know.
你怎么会被抓 ? 我也不知道
You look beautiful.
你真漂亮
It's bad luck for the groom to see the bride before the wedding.
新郎在婚礼前见新娘会倒霉的
Make way! Let me through! How dare you!
让开 让我过去 好大的胆子
Stand your men down at once. Do you hear me?
命令他们退下 听到没有
Governor Weatherby Swann, it's been too long.
史总督 久违了
- Cutler Beckett? - It's Lord now, actually.
贝克特? 我封瑞了 叫我阁下
Lord or not, you have no reason and no authority to arrest this man.
管你是不是 你没有权力逮捕这个人
In fact. ldo. Mr. Mercer? a
我当然有这权力 莫先生
The warrant for the arrest of one William Turner.
这是威廉. 杜纳的拘捕令
- This warrant is for Elizabeth Swann. - Is it? That's annoying. My mistake.
这是伊丽落白.史旺的拘捕令 是吗 妈的 再错了
- Arrest her. - On what charges?
还捕她 什么罪名 ?
Aha. Here's the one for William Turner.
这才是威廉. 杜纳的拘捕令
And I have another one for a Mr. James Norrington.
另外还要还捕倪灵上顿
- Is he present? - What are the charges?
他人呢? 什么罪名 ?
Commodore Norrington resigned his commission some months ago.
倪准将几个月前就退役了
That wasn't the answer to the question I asked.
你没回答我的问题
Lord Beckett. In the category of questions not answered...
贝阁下 你也没有回答他的问题
We are under the jurisdiction of the king's governor of Port Royal
家有家规 国有国法
and you will tell us what we are charged with.
我们的罪名是什么
The charge is "conspiring to set free
罪名是「图谍解救一名
"a man convicted of crimes against the Crown and Empire
因触犯大英帝国王法
"and condemned to death. a for which the...”
而被处以绞刑的死刑犯 因此1
For which the punishment, regrettably, is also death.
因此动因者也将被判处死弄
Perhaps you remember a certain pirate named Jack Sparrow.
你记得杰克“'史派洛这个海盗吧
Captain.
他是船长
Captain Jack Sparrow.
杰克 . 史派洛船长
Yes, [ thought you might.
我就知道你们记得他
Fifteen men on a dead man’s chest
五十名海盗锁在聚魂棺
Yo-ho-ho and a bottle of rum
只有一撼兰姆酒来做伴
Drink and the devil had done for the rest
痛饮后就被阎王抓去估
Prisoners. come on! a
快点 !
Sorry, mate.
抱火 老兄
Mind if we make a little side trip?
介意我改变航向吗?
I didn't think so.
一定不介意吧
- Not quite according to plan. - Complications arose, ensued,
原来的计划不是这样 出了点小状况
were overcome.
不过现在搞定了
You got what you went in for, then?
东西拿到手了吗 ?
Captain, I think the crew, meaning me as well,
船长 鬼盗船的船员 包括我
were expecting something a bit more shiny,
都认为你拿回更值钱的东西
with the Isla de Muerta going pear-shaped, reclaimed by the sea with the treasure.
上炊在死亡之岛空手而蚊 宝藏都沉入大海了
And the Royal Navy chasing us around the Atlantic.
还被皇家海军穷追不会
- And the hurricane. - Aye.
然后又碰上风风 是这样
Allin all, it seems some time a since we did a speck of honest pirating.
总之 我们好久没有烧杀据掠了
- Shiny. - Aye. shiny.
值钱的东西 对 值钱的东西
Is that how you're all feeling?
你们都这么想?
That perhaps dear old Jack is not serving your best interests as captain?
我没让你们捞到好处
Walk the plank.
走跳板 !
- What did the bird say? - Do not blame the bird.
那只策鸟说什么 别怪它
Show us what is on that piece of cloth there.
那块布上面有什么 ?
- You know that don't do no good. - It does me.
你射不死他 我觉得快活就行了
- It's a key. - No. Much more better.
是一把钥是 这并不是一把钥晤
Itis a drawing of a key.
而是一把钥是的图型
Gentlemen, a
各位
what do keys do?
人钥是是用来干什么的?
Keys
人铀是吗 ?
unlock things?
用来开锁 ?
And whatever this key unlocks, inside there's something valuable.
人钥是能打开倘住的宝藏
So we're setting out to find whatever this key unlocks.
咱们就是要去找这东西
No.
不
If we con't have the key, we can't open whatever we don't have that it unlocks.
没有人铀是什么都找不到
So what purpose would be served in finding whatever need be unlocked,
我们不先找出真的钥是
which we don't have. without first a having found the key what unlocks it?
就找不到被锁住的宝藏
So we're going after this key.
那我们就去找钥晤
You're not making any sense at all.
你根本就是胡说八道
Any more questions?
还有什么问题吗
So do we have a heading?
那船往哪儿开 ?
A heading.
往哪儿
Set sail ina
准备起航
general
航向是…
that-way direction.
那边
Captain?
船长
Come on, snap to and make sail. You know how this works. Go on.
你们是老手了 快去扬帆 快
Have you noticed lately
你最近注意到没有
the captain seems to be acting a bit strange... er?
船长有点奇怪
Setting sail without knowing his own heading.
不知航向就起航
Something's got Jack vexed, and mark my words,
他一定得了失心病
what bodes ill for Jack Sparrow bodes ill for us all.
那咱们都会倒大霉
Lord Beckett. a the prisoner as ordered, sir.
贝阁下 囚犯带来了
Those won't be necessary.
把手错拿掉
The East India Trading Company has need of your services.
东印度公司有事情要你做
We wish for you to act as our agent
我们想你做中间人
in a business transaction with our mutual friend Captain Sparrow.
输我们的朋友史船长谈谈
More acquaintance. How do you know him?
我们不熟 你怎么认识他的
We've had dealings in the past.
我们曾经打过交道
And we've each left our mark on the other.
我和他曾在对方的身上留下记号
What mark did he leave on you?
他怎么在你身上留下记号的
By your efforts, Jack Sparrow was set free.
你上次劫狱把他救走
I would like you to go to him
这灾我要你找到他
and recover a certain property in his possession.
从他手上拿回一样东西
Recover. At the point of a sword?
该是抢回来吧
Bargain.
讨价还价
Letters of marque.
特许证
You will offer what amounts to a full pardon.
你要答应赦免他
Jack will be free. a a privateer in the employ of England.
还他自由 让他成为大英帝国武装民船船长
Somehow I doubt Jack will consider employment the same as being free.
他才不会不要自申替你做事
Freedom.
自申不值钱
Jack Sparrow is a dying breed.
他的想法落伍了
The world is shrinking,
我们征服了全世界
the blank edges of the map filled in.
世界都在我们掌握之中
Jack must find his place in the New World or perish.
如果他不识相点 就死定了
Not unlike you, Mr. Turner.
但你不一样 杜先生
You and your fiancée face the hangman's noose.
你和未婚麦被判处绞刑
- So you get Jack and the Black Pearl. - The Black Pearl?
所以你要找到杰克船长和鬼盗船 和鬼盗船?
- The property you want that he possesses. - A ship? Hardly.
你要的是鬼盗船? 我要那破船有什么用?
The item in question is considerably smaller and far more valuable. a
我要的东西很小 但很值钱
A compass?
是个罗盘吧?
You know it.
你应该很清楚的
Bring back that compass or there's no deal.
把罗盘拿回来 不然你们就等死吧
Why is the rum always gone?
为什么老是没有兰姆酒 ?
That's why.
原来如此
As you were, gents.
各位继续吧
Time's run out. Jack. a
你快玩完了 杰克
Bootstrap.
鞋带?
Bill Turner.
比尔杜纳 ?
You look good, Jack.
你气色不错
Is this a dream?
我在做梦
No.
不是
I thought not. If it were, there'd be rum. a
我猜也不是 不然就不会有酒
You got the Pear! back, I see.
你把鬼盗船抢回来了
l had some help retrieving the Peari, by the way.
有一个人帮我把它抢回来了
Your son.
你的儿子
William?
威尔?
He ended up a pirate after all.
他还当了海盗
And to what clo I owe the pleasure of your carbuncle?
你来找我什么事 ?
He sent me.
是他派我来的
Davy Jones.
深海阎王
So it's you, then.
你是他的特使
He shanghaied you into service. eh? a
他逼你替他做事 ?
I'm sorry for the part I played in the mutiny against you, Jack.
很抱火当年我也参与叛变
I stood up for you.
不过我蔡你说过好话
Everything went wrong after that.
没想到他们连我也出卖了
They strapped me to a cannon. l ended up on the bottom of the ocean,
我被绑在炮弹上 沉入海底
the weight of the water crushing down on me.
不管我怎么挣扎
Unable to move.
都动弹不得
Unable to die. Jack. a
死也死不了
And I thought that even the tiniest hope of escaping this fate, would take it.
当时只要能逃生 我什么都愿意接受
would trade anything for it.
我愿意用任何东西来交换
It's funny what a man will do to forestall his final judgment.
为了活命人什么都做得出
You made a deal with him too, Jack. a
你也和深海阎王交换条件
He raised the Pear! from the depths for you.
他帮你得到鬼盗船
13 years, you've been her captain.
让你当了1 3年的船长
- Technically... - Jack.
其实呢
You won't be able to talk yourself out of this.
这炊你不能赁三寸不烂之理脱身
The terms what applied to me apply to you as well.
你跟我一样要信宇承诺
One soul bound to crew 100 years upon his ship.
在深海阎王的船上服役一百年
The Flying Dutchman already has a captain...
幽衬飞船已经有船长了
Then it's the locker for you!
那你就得被埋在海底
Jones's terrible leviathan will find you
深海韶王的海怪会找到你
and drag the Pear! back to the depths and you along with it.
把你和鬼盗船带到海底深渊
Any idea when Jones might release said terrible beastie?
深海阎王几时会派出这支海怪 ?
l already told you, Jack.
我一开始就说了
Your time is up.
你的大限已到
It comes now. a
凶狠的食人海怪已经出击
drawn with ravenous hunger to the man what bears the black spot.
它的目标是身上有黑点的人
On deck, all hands! a Make fast the bunt gasket!
各就各位 系好帆脚绳子
On deck! Scurry!
大人饮快到甲板
Scurry! l want movement! Movement! I want movement!
动作快点
Lift the skin up! Keep your loof! Haul those sheets!
快把船饥拉起来 拉起纵饥 道凤航行
Run them! Run! Keep running! Run as if the devil himself and itself is upon us!
恶魔紧追不爹 赶快甩掉它
- Do we have a heading? - Run! Land.
航向那里 陆地
- Which port? - l didn't say “port,” I said "land." Any land.
哪一座港口 ? 我没说港口 任何陆地都行
- Jack's hat! Bring her about! - No. no! a
杰克的船长蛋 快调头 别管它
Leave it!
算了
Run.
快走吧
Back to your stations, the lot of you!
大伙回到岗位
dack?
杰克 ?
For the love of mother and child. Jack. oe what's coming after us?
拜托你告诉我 有什么在追我们 ?
Nothing.
没什么
- Here, now, you can't be here. - [ think you'll find he can.
你不能进来 当然可以
Mr. Swann!
史先生
Governor Swann. still. a
我还是史总督
Do you think I wear this wig to keep my head warm?
不然我戴假发是为了取暖吗 ?
Jack's compass? What coes Beckett want with that?
杰克的罗盘 贝克特要它干六 ?
Does it matter? I'm to find Jack and convince him to return to Port Royal.
这有估系吗 我要找到杰克 把他带回来
In exchange, the charges against us will be dropped.
这样我们就能脱罪
No. We must find our own avenue to secure your freedom.
我们要用其它的方法逃出去
Is that a lack of faith in Jack or in me?
你对我和杰克没信心 ?
That you would risk your life to save Sparrow
上灾你冒生命危险救杰克
does not mean he would do the same for anyone else.
不代表他会想报恩
Now, where is that dog with the keys?
那只咬着钥是的狗呢?
I have faith in you.
我对你有信心
Both of you.
我对你们俩有信心
Where will you find him?
你要到哪里找他 ?
Tortuga. I'll start there and I won't stop searching till I find him.
土图嘉港 找不到他我决不轩体
And then I intend to return here to marry you.
然后我会回来要你
- Properly? - Eagerly, if you'll still have me.
举行正式婚礼 ? 如果你还愿意的话
If it weren't for these bars. a I'd have you already.
要不是被监禁 我早就嫁给你了
- I'll wait for you. - Keep a weather eye on the horizon.
我等你回来 盯着海平线等着我回来
Captain Jack Sparrow?
史杰克船长?
Owes me four doubloons. Heard he was dead.
他六我四块金币 听说他变封了
Singapore. That's what I heard. Drunk. with a smile on his face. a
他去了新加坡 日子舒服得很
Sure as the tide. Jack Sparrow turn up in Singapore.
我背定他去新加坡了
Jack Sparrow?
史杰克 ?
l haven't seen him in a month.
一个月没他消息了
When you find him, will you give him a message?
你找到他 帮我把这个带给他
Can't say about Jack Sparrow,
我不知道史杰克的下落
but there’s an island just south of the straits
不过海峡南边有个小岛
where I trade spice for
我拿香蕉交换
delicious long pork.
超好吃的人肉
Cannot say about Jack, but you'll find a ship there.
杰克不一定在 但有一盘船
A ship with black sails.
一盘挂黑帆的船
My brother will take you ashore.
我兄弟会带你上着
- What's wrong? The beach is there. - C'est trop dangereux.
怎么了 海滩在哪 ? 这里太危险了
- What? - C'est trop dangereux. je vous l'avais dit.
什么 ? 我说这里太危险了
Bon voyage. monsieur.
祝你一路顺风(法文)
Jack!
杰克 !
Jack Sparrow!
史杰克 !
Marty!
马蒂 !
Cotton!
小卡!
Anybody?
有人吗?
A familiar face.
终于看到熟人了
Don't eat me.
别吃我
- I'm not going to eat you. - Don't eat me.
我不吃你
No. Don't eat me.
不 别吃我
Gibbs.
吉下
Come on! Let's go!
来呀 上啊
Come on! Who wants it?
谁想先上?
I can do this all day!
我这样可以撑过一整天
dack?
杰克 ?
Jack Sparrow!
史杰克
I can honestly say I'm glad to see you.
我这灾是真的很高兴看到你
Jack, it's me. a
杰克 是我啊
Tell them to let me down!
叫他们把我放下来
.eensy-weensy.
(土语)
Jack, the compass. That's alll need.
杰克 我只需要你的罗盘
Elizabeth is in danger. We were arrested for helping you.
伊丽莎白有难 我们因救你而被捕
She faces the gallows!
她会被吊死
Savvy?
懂吧
Jack, what did you tell them?
你和他们说了什么
No!
不 !
What about Elizabeth?
伊丽莎白怎么办?
Jack!
杰克 !
That's a good girl. Come a little closer.
美女 过来点
- We don't bite. - Go on. We won't bite you.
我们不会咬人 过来点 我们不会咬人
Come quickly.
快走
- Tell me what's happening. - Our name still has some standing.
怎么了? 你老和苞宝刀未老
I've arranged passage to England. The captain is a friend of mine.
我要送你到英国 船长是我朋友
No! Will's gone to find Jack!
不 威尔去找杰克 了
We cannot count on William Turner.
那小子靠不住
- Come! - He's better than you give him credit for.
快走吧 他比你想象的可靠
This is no time for innocence. Beckett has offered one pardon only -
没时间要脾气了
one, and that is promised to Jack Sparrow.
贝克特只答应赦免史杰克
Even if Will succeeds. a
就算感尔找到他
do not ask me to endure the sight of my daughter walking to the gallows. Do not.
我也不能让女儿上绞台
Perhaps I can ensure a fair trial for Will if he returns.
威尔回来 我会回来安排公平审判
- A fair trial for Will ends in a hanging. - Then there is nothing left for you here.
那他只有死路一条 你留下来也一样
Wait inside.
留在马车上
Captain?
船长?
Evening, Governor.
您好 总督大人
Shame, that. a
没办法
He was carrying this.
他要去送信
It's a letter to the king.
一封给英王的信
- It's from you. - No...
你送的信呢 不
Elizabeth.
伊丽莎和白
What are you doing?
你在干六 ?
- Where is she? - Who?
她人呢 ? 谁?
No doubt you've discovered that loyalty is no longer the currency of the realm,
这年头没人会患心
as your father believes.
你父亲也被他骗了
Then what is?
这算什么 ?
I'm afraid currency is the currency of the realm.
这年头一切向钱看
l expect, then, we can come to some sort of understanding.
那我们就有共识了
- I'm here to negotiate. - I'm listening.
我是来谈条件的 我在听
I'm listening intently.
洗耳茶听
These letters of marque are signed by the king.
这信有英王的亲笔签名
Yes, and they're not valid until they bear my signature and my seal.
我要签名盖章才能生效
Or else I would not still be here.
所以你才没逃走
You sent Will to get you the compass owned by Jack Sparrow.
你派感尔去拿杰克的罗盘
- It will do you no good. - Do explain.
那罗盘对你没用 说明自点
l have been to the Isla de Muerta. l have seen the treasure myself.
我去过死亡之岛 看到了宝藏
- There is something you need to know. -lsee.
我想你该知道一些事 原来如此
You think the compass leads only to the Isla de Muerta
你以为罗盘只会指向死亡之岛
and so you hope to save me from an evil fate.
所以要救我一命
But you mustn't worry.
请你放心
I care not for cursed Aztec gold.
我才不想要受诅咒的金币
My desires are not so provincial.
我有更大的野心
There's more than one chest of value in these waters.
海底并不是只有一个藏宝箱
So perhaps you may wish to enhance your offer.
我建议你提出更好的条件
Consider into your calculations that you robbed me of my wedding night.
你破坏了我美好的婚礼
So I did.
对
A marriage interrupted
一个未完成的婚礼
or fate intervenes?
这是命中注定的
You're making great efforts to ensure Jack Sparrow's freedom.
原来你这么做是想 证史杰克重获自由
- These aren't going to Jack. - Really?
我不是为了杰克 真的?
To ensure Mr. Turner's freedom. then, ee
如果你想救杜纳先生
I'll still want that compass.
我还是想那个罗盘
Consider that in your calculations.
这点你也要考虑清楚
I say it was Divine Providence what escaped us from jail.
我们能逃出来真是老天有限
And I say it was me being clever.
是我够聪明
Ain't that right, poochie?
对吧 狗狗?
Well, how'd you know it weren't Divine Providence what inspired you to be clever?
你怎么知道这不是注定的?
Anyways, l ain't stealing no ship.
反正我都不偷这船
It ain't stealing. It's salvaging. And since when did you care?
这不算偷 是资源回收 你什么时候变成好人了?
Since we're not immortal no more. We gotta take care of our immortal souls.
我们不再是活死人了 要靠圣经来解救
- You know you can't read. - It's the Bible. You get credit for trying.
你又不识字 有圣经就能得救
Pretending to read the Bible's a lie. That's a mark against...
假装读圣经会遵天谴 这是衣污神灵
Look.
你看
There it is.
在那儿
What's got into him?
它是怎么了
Must have seen a catfish.
一定能看到一条鱼
Stupid mongrel!
策狗
Come on!
快点
- It's ours for the taking. - Tide’s coming in. That should help.
船是我们的了 涨潮了 刚好
And salvaging is saving, in a manner of speaking.
资源回收也算是揉救的一种
There's the truth of it!
完全正确
Suppose we better save it as Soon as we can. a
动作越快越好
what with our souls in such a vulnerable state and all.
我们的灵魂很脆弱
Amen to that.
说得好
Thank you.
谢了
Why would he do this to us? If Jack is the chief...
他干癖把我们估起来 如果杰克是菌长
Aye. the Pelegostos made Jack their chief. a
要是他不遵守游戏规则
but he only remains chief as long as he acts like a chief.
食人族就会把他废掉
So he had no choice. He's a captive as much as the rest of us.
那时他也会沦为阶下囚
Worse, as it turns out. See, the Pelegostos believe that Jack is a god in human form,
也许更惨 食人族认为杰克是神
and they intend to do him the honor of releasing him from his fleshy prison.
他们打算让他抛弃臭皮圳
They'll roast him and eat him.
把他糯了吃掉
Where's the rest of the crew?
其他人呢?
These cages we're in weren't built till after we got here.
你想这些骨头笼子怎么来的
The feast is about to begin.
食人族大餐即将开始
Jack's life will end
鼓声一停
when the drums stop.
杰克就定了
Well, we can't just sit here and wait, then. can we? a
我们不能不帮他
No, no. Oi! No, no. re
喂 不要这样
More wood. Big fire. Big fire.
多添 点木材 把火礁烧大点
lam Chief. Want big fire.
我是商长 我要大火堆
Come on.
快点
Tout de suite. Come on. More wood.
快点 多添木材
Bugger.
惨了
A little seasoning, eh?
加一点香料
Well done.
二得好
Put your legs through. Start to climb!
把脚伸出去 快息呀
Come on. men! a It ll take all of us to crew the Black Pearl!
加油 ! 开鬼盗船需要每个人出力
Actually, you wouldn't need everyone.
其实不需要每个人
About six would do.
只要六个人就能开船
Oh, dear. a
完了
- Hurry! - Come on!
快点 快呀
Come on! Is that all you got?
加油 没劲了?
Wait. Stop.
停下来
- What are they doing? - Stop.
他们在干骂 ? 停下
Snake!
蛇 !
Move!
快走!
Well, go on, go get them.
快去抓他们
No, no. Oi! No, no! re
不要
Not good.
情况不妙
Cut it loose! Find a rock!
找块石头 把它砸断
Roll the cage!
用滚的
Come on!
快点
- Lift the cage! Hurry! - Come on, lads. Lift it like a lady's skirt.
快把笼子抬起来 就像捧起女人的裙子一样
Run!
快跑!
This way, lads!
这里
Take cover!
躲起来
Stop it!
住手
Bugger.
惨了
Thief! Little hairy thief! Give it back!
小毛贼 还给我
- Don't bite it! - Haul loose the mooring line!
别咬它 把系缆索松开
He's got me eye. He won't give it back.
他拿了我的眼珠不还我
- How'd you get it back last time? - Excellent! Our work's half done.
你上灵怎么拿回来的? 就快成功了
We done it for you, knowing you'd be coming back.
我知道你们会回来的
- Make ready to sail, boys! - What about Jack?
准备起航 那杰克呢 ?
l won't leave without him.
我不能丢下他不管
- Time to go. - Cast off those lines!
该走了 松开缆绳
Make ready to cast off!
准备起航
Good doggy.
乖狗
Alas, my children, this is the day you shall always remember as the day you almost...
孩几们永远记住今天 你们差点抓住
Captain Jack Sparrow.
风电大名的史杰克船长
Let's get away from this island and head out to open sea.
快离开这和鬼地方 驶向大海
Yes to the first. Yes to the second. but a only insofar as we keep to the shallows.
说得好 不过要离海岸远点
That seems a bit contradictory, Captain.
这有点自相矛盾
I have faith in your reconciliatory navigational skills.
我对你的航海术有信心
Now, where is that monkey? I want to shoot something.
臭猴子 我要射死它
Jack. Elizabeth is in danger.
杰克 伊丽莎白有危险
Have you considered just locking her up somewhere?
不如把她估起来比较安全
She is locked up, bound to hang for helping you.
她因救你而被人关进大补
There comes a time when one must take responsibility for one’s mistakes.
人总要为自己犯的错负责
I need that compass of yours, Jack.
我要用你的罗盘
I must trace it for her freedom.
交换她的自申
- Mr. Gibbs. - Captain.
吉下先生 船长
We have a need to travel upriver.
我们必须递流而上
By need, do you mean a trifling need?
这是你灵光一闪的决定吗 ?
Fleeting? As in, say, a passing fancy?
你又是一时心血来潮吗 ?
No, a resolute and unyielding need.
不 这是一定要的
What we need to do is make sail for Port Royal with all haste.
我们必须驶回皇家港
William. a
威廉
I shall trade you the compass
我答应把罗盘给你
if you will help me
只要你帮我找到
- You want me to find this? - No.
你要我找到这东西 ? 不是
You want you to find this,
是你自己一定要找到它
because the finding of this finds you incapacitorially finding
因为你只要找到它
and’or locating in your discovering a way to save your dolly belle, ol’ what's-her-face.
就绝对可以救你的心上人 我总了她叫什么
Savvy?
懂吗 ?
This is going to save Elizabeth?
这把钥是能救伊丽落和白?
How much cdo you know about Davy Jones?
你对深海净王了解多少?
Not much.
不多
Yeah, it's going to save Elizabeth.
这就对了 这能救伊丽落和白
What's all this?
这是怎么回事?
If you both fancy the dress, you'll just have to share and wear it one after the other.
你们都喜欢的话就一起穿吧
It's not like that. sir. a This ship is haunted.
不是 这艘船冰鬼
Is it, now? And you?
是吗 你说呢 ?
There's a female presence amongst us here, sir.
船上有个女鬼
All the men, they can feel it.
大伙都感觉得到
It's the ghost of a lady widowed before her marriage. I figure it,
这个女鬼刚嫁人就守活赛
searching for her husband, lost at sea.
一直在海上找死去的老公
A virgin too, likely as not.
她背定还是处女
And that bodles ill by all accounts.
这会带来厄运
I say that we throw the dress overboard and we hope the spirit follows it.
那就把婚纱丢下海 希望女鬼也跟着下去
No! That will just anger the spirit, sir.
这么做只会激怒她
What we need to do is find out what the spirit needs, and then get it back to her.
我们得知道她要什么 然后还给她
Enough! Enough!
够了
You're a pair of superstitious goats and it's got the best of you.
你们太迷信了
Now, this appears to be no more as we have a stowaway on board.
在我看来 船上有个偷渡客
A young woman, by the look of it.
而且是个年轻女子
I want you to search the ship and find her.
把她给搜出来
Oh, and she's probably naked.
她全身一定光溜溜
Why is Jack afraid of the open ocean?
杰克为什么害怕大海 ?
Well, if you believe such things,
有一种传说
there's a beast does the bidding of Davy Jones -
深海疝王能指使一只大海怪
a fearsome creature with giant tentacles that'll suction your face clean off
这只可怕海怪的巨大触角 能把你的脸撕烂
and drag an entire ship down to the crushing darkness.
甚至把一整艘船拖到漆黑海底
The kraken.
海怪
They say the stench of its breath is like...
听说它会发出恶臭气息
Imagine, the last thing you know on God's green earth
这世上最令人吓破胆的东西
is the roar of the kraken and the reeking odor of a thousand rotting corpses.
就是海怪的怒吼和它口中 发出的千年腐尸恶臭
If you believe such things.
如果你能相信这些事的话
And the key will spare him that?
那把钥是能救她一命?
Well, that's the very question Jack wants answered.
杰克也很想知道答案
Bad enough even to go visit
情况糟到要去见
her.
她
Her?
她?
Aye.
对
No worries. mates. a Tia Dalma and I go way back.
好了 伙计 我各亚女巫作系很好
Thick as thieves. Nigh inseparable, we are.
有一阵子简直难舍难分
Were. Have been.
不过那是以前的事了
Before.
以前的事了
- I'll watch your back. - It's me front I'm worried about.
我在后面掩扩你 我担心我前面
Mind the boat.
你负责留守
Jack Sparrow.
史杰克
Tia Dalma.
绢亚女和焉
l always knew the wind was going to blow you back to me one day.
我就知道有一天你会找上门
You...
你
You have a touch of
你和未来的命运
destiny about you,
息息相估
William Turner.
威廉.杜纳
You know me?
你认识我?
You want to know me.
你才认识我
There'll be no knowing here. We've come for help and we're not leaving without it.
不认识 我们是请你来帮忙的
- [ thought I knew you. - Not so well as I had hoped.
我还以为我很了解你呢 还没到我期望的程度
- Come.
来吧
What service may I do you?
我能帮你们什么 ?
- You know I demand payment. - [brought payment.
你也知道我的酬劳不低 我把酬劳带来了
Look.
你看
An undead monkey.
一只不死的臭猴子
Top that.
够炫吧
Don't! You've no idea how long it took us to catch that.
咱们费尽心思才还到它
We're looking for this.
我们在找这个
And what it goes to.
还有它能打开的东西
The compass you bartered from me, it cannot lead you to this?
你从我这儿换来的罗盘 都指引不了方向?
Maybe. Why?
也许 干骂问?
Jack Sparrow does not know what he wants.
也许你不知道你要的是什么
Or do you know,
也许你知道
but are loath to claim it as your own?
只是没胆把它贞为己有
Your key go to a chest.
这是一个箱子的钥晤
And it is what lay inside the chest you seek, don't it?
你要的是箱子里面的东西 ?
- What is inside? - Gold?
里面有什么 ? 金银?
Jewels? Unclaimed properties of a valuable nature?
珠宝 还是稀世罕有的宝贝?
Nothing bad, I hope?
最好不是不祥之物
You know of Davy Jones,
深海阎王
yes?
你们知道什么 ?
A man of the sea.
他是天生的水手
A great sailor,
伟大的航海家
until he run afoul of that which vex all men.
直到他泪上一样东西 车和志了一伙人
What vexes all men?
他泪上了什么 ?
What indeed?
到底是什么 ?
- The sea. - Sums.
大海吗? 分赃不均 ?
The dichotomy of good and evil.
不分好歹 ?
A woman.
一个女人
He fell in love.
他爱上了一个女人
No, no. no. no. a heard it was the sea he fell in love with.
不 我只听说他爱大海
Same story, different versions, and all are true.
说法不同 实质一样 他们说得都对
See, it was a woman a
他爱上的女人
as changing and harsh
情绪善变 无理取闹
and untamable as the sea.
就和大海一样无法驯服
Him never stopped loving her.
但他仍然深爱她
But the pain it cause him was too much to live with
内心的痛苦生不如死
but not enough to cause him to die.
可是他又死不了
What exactly did he put into the chest?
他到底在箱子里装了什么 ?
Him heart.
他的心
Literally or figuratively?
是真的心还是比喻?
He couldn't literally put his heart in a chest.
他不可能把比喻放进箱子里
Could he?
真的?
It was not worth feeling what small, fleeting joy life brings.
人生短暂的欢乐对他来说不够
And so
于是
him carve out him heart. a
他接出自己的心脏
lock it away in a chest and hicle the chest from the world.
人锁进一个箱子 把它沈入海底
The key
这把钥是
he keep with him at all times.
他一直带在身边
- You knew this. - [did not. I didn't know where the key was.
你早就知道了 不 以前我不知道
But now we do. All that's left is to climb aboard the Flying Dutchman, grab the key,
但现在知道了 咱们只要到那拿了钥是
you go back to Port Royal and save your bonnie lass, eh?
就能回皇家港口救你的心上人骂
Let me see your hand.
把手伸出来给我看
The black spot!
黑点
- The black spot! - Black spot!
黑点上
My eyesight's as good as ever, just so you know.
我又没近视 看得到
I have just the thing. Now, where did I put it?
我有样法宝 它在哪儿呢
My little beauty, where are you?
我的宝贝 你在哪儿
Such a long time in such a mess.
一直被埋在这玲垃级下面
Davy Jones cannot make port.
深海阎王不能停靠港口
Cannot step on land but once every ten years.
每隔十年才能上兰
Land is where you are safe, Jack Sparrow,
你在陆地上很安全
and so you will carry land with you.
所以你要随身携带着泥土
Dirt.
泥土
- This is a jar of dirt. - Yes.
这是一负泥土 没错
Is the jar of dirt going to help?
这负泥土有什么用?
If you don't want it, give it back.
你不要就还给我
- No. - Then it helps.
不 那它就很有用
It seems we have a need to find the Flying Dutchman.
看来我们要找到幽衬飞船
A touch of destiny.
这是命中注定
That's the Flying Dutchman?
那就是幽实飞船?
- She doesn't look like much. - Neither do you.
看起来不怎么样癖 你也一样
Do not underestimate her.
千万别低估她
- Must have run afoul of the reef. - So, what's your plan, then?
她一定搁浅在礁岩上 你有什么计划 ?
l row over, search the ship until find your bloody key.
划过去 到处搜 找到钥是
And if there are crewmen?
船上有人怎么办?
I cut down anyone in my path.
谁敢挡路 格杀勿论
l like it. Simple, easy to remember.
我喜欢 简单易懂
Your chariot awaits you, Sire.
您的战船 大将军
If you do happen to get captured, just say Jack Sparrow sent you to settle his debt.
如果你不小心被抓住 就说史杰克派你来还债
- It might save your life. - Bon voyage!
这能保住你一条小命 一路顺风
Douse the lamps.
估灯
Sailor.
水手
- Hoisting the jib, Captain's orders. - Sailor!
收山 船长的命令 水手!
Hoisting the jib. Bring up with a round turn.
收帆 立刻停船
There's no use. You've run aground.
没用的 你们的船搁浅了
No.
才没有
Beneath us.
真正的船在海底
Foul breath.
臭小子
Down on your marrowbones and pray.
跪下来祷告吧
Get back! Get back!
退后 退后 !
Five men still alive. The rest have moved on.
五个还活着 其他都挂了
Do you fear death?
你怕死吗 ?
Do you fear that dark abyss?
你怕蔡入漆黑深渊吗 ?
All your deeds laid bare.
你的所作所为无所通形
All your sins punished.
你的罪行将受乱罚
I can offer you
我可以放你
an escape.
一条生路
Don't listen to him!
别听他的话
Do you not fear death?
难道你不怕死?
I'll take my chances, sir.
我愿意冒这个险
To the depths.
把他丢下大海
Cruel blackguard!
你真是残酷无情
Life is cruel.
人生本来就很残酷
Why should the afterlife be any different?
死后为什么要有差别 ?
l offer you a choice.
我给你一个选择
Join my crew
加入我的行列
and postpone the judgment.
就不会受到上帝审判
One hundred years before the mast.
在我的船上做一百年的劳工
Will ye serve?
你愿意吗 ?
I will serve.
我愿意
You are neither dead nor dying.
你不是活死人 也不会死
What is your purpose here?
你来有什么目的?
Jack Sparrow sent me to settle his debt.
史杰克派我来还债
What is your purpose here?
你到底有什么目的?
Did he. now? a
是吗?
I'm sorely tempted to accept that offer.
我倒是很想接受这个条件
You have a debt to pay.
你久我一笔俩
You've been captain of the Black Pear! for 13 years.
我让你当13年的鬼盗船船长
That was our agreement.
这是我们谈好的条件
Technically l was only captain for two years, then I was mutinied upon.
其实我只干了两年船长 后来就被船员出卖
Then you were a poor captain, but a captain nonetheless.
这证明你很盖 但你仍是船长
Have you not introduced yourself all these years
这些年来你不都自称
as Captain Jack Sparrow?
史杰克船长吗?
You have my payment. One soul to serve on your ship.
我已经付了 他的命还我的债
One soul is not equal to another.
他的命跟你的不同
We've established my proposal is sound in principle. Now we're haggling over price.
至少这个提议不错 咱们继续讨价还价吧
Price?
讨价还价 ?
Just how many souls do you think my soul is worth?
我的一条命值多少条命?
One hundred souls.
一百条人命
Three days.
我给你三天时间
You're a diamond. mate. Send me back a the boy. I'll get started right off.
你人真好 把那小子送回来
l keep the boy. A good-faith payment.
我要把他留下来 当作订人金
That leaves you only 99 more to go.
你还欠我99条命
Have you not met Will Turner?
威廉. 杜纳可不是泛泛之募
He's noble, heroic. a a terrific soprano.
他是大英雄
Worth at least four.
至少值四条人命
Maybe three and a half.
也许三条半吧
And did l happen to mention
我有没有提到
he’s in love?
他爱上一个人 ?
With a girl.
一个女人
Due to be married.
他们正打算成亲
Betrothed.
结为连理
Dividing him from her and her from him would only be half as cruel
把这对金童玉女活活拆散
as actually allowing them to be joined in holy matrimony. Eh?
比让他们永世结为夫妻更仁慈 对吧?
Il keep the boy. 99 souls.
我要留下他 你欠我99条命
But I wonder, Sparrow,
不过我要问你
can you live with this?
你对得起自己的良心吗 ?
Can you condemn an innocent man, a friend. a
你忍心让你这善良忠心的朋友 永世不得超生
to a lifetime of servitude in your name while you roam free?
自己却遂区自在地享福吗 ?
Yep. I'm good with it.
当然 没问题
Shall we seal it in blood? I mean ink.
秋血为盟 我是说敌血为盟
Three days.
三天
- Mr. Gibbs. - Aye.
吉下先生 在
I feel sullied and unusual.
我觉得很过意不去
And how do you intend to harvest these 99 souls in three days?
你怎么在3天内弄到99条人命
Fortunately, he was mum as to the condition in which these souls need be.
幸好他没指定要谁的命
Tortuga.
土图嘉港
It's an outrage. Port tariffs, berthing fees,
太过份了 港夫费 停泊费
wharf handling and, heaven help us, pilotage.
码头管理费和领航费
Are we all to work for the East India Trading Company, then?
钱都给东印度公司淹走了
I'm afraid, sir, Tortuga is the only free port left in these waters.
土图嘉港是唯一剩下的自申港
A pirate port is what you mean. Well, I'm sorry.
你是说海岛港 算了 不跟你计较
An honest sailor is what lam. l make my living fair and I sleep well each night.
我可是奉公守法的船长 实实在在赚钱 晚上取得安稳
Sir!
船长 !
She wants you to do something.
她要你做一件事
She's trying to give a sign.
她在发出一个征兆
Over there! Look for a sign!
那里 快去看
Look, there! There it is! a
椎 在那里
- There's the sign! - That's seaweed.
征兆 那是海草而已
- Seaweed can be a sign. - Looks like entrails.
海草也可以是征兆 看起来像是内脏
- That would be a bad sign. - What's that over there?
那可能是不祥之兆 那是什么 ?
And what makes you think you're worthy to crew the Black Pear!?
你够资格当鬼盗船的船长吗
I've never sailed a day in me life.
老实说 我没当过船员
I figure I should get out, see the world while I'm still young.
我只是想趁年轻见见世面
You'll do. Make your mark. Next!
好了 画押 下一个
My wife ran off with my dog
我老朔带着小狗跑了
and I'm drunk for a month
我借酒涪起整整一个月
and I don't give an ass rat's
我才不在卑
if l live or die.
自己的死活
- Perfect. Next! - [Know what I want. [ Know what I want...
太好了 下一个 我知道我要什么了
- Me have one arm and a bum leg. - It's the crow’s nest for you.
我只剩一只手一只脚 你适合当随望员
- [Know what I want. - Next!
我知道我要什么 下一个
Ever since I was a little lad. a I've always wanted to sail the seas forever.
我从小就一直想邀游四海
Sooner than you think. Sign the roster.
快成功了 签名
Thanks very much.
多谢了
- How we going? - Including those four, that gives us four.
怎么样 ? 那四个算在内 只有四个
And what's your story?
你又有什么故事 ?
My story.
我的故事
It's exactly the same as your story, just one chapter behind.
就跟你一样 就是晚了一步
I chased a man across the seven seas.
我在五湖四海追逐一个人
The pursuit cost me my crew,
割我失去我的船员
soe my commission,
职位
and my life.
甚至我的生命
- Commodore? - No, not anymore. Weren't you listening?
准将 已经不是了 你没在听吗
I nearly had you all off Tripoli.
我在的黎波里差点就带到你们
I would have. a if not for the hurricane.
要不是趾风就成功了
Lord.
老天
You didn't try to sail through it?
你没试着穿越叮风吧 ?
So, dol make your crew
我到底
or not?
能不能当你们的船员 ?
You haven't said where you're going.
你没说你们要去哪里?
Somewhere nice?!
是不是好地方 ?
So, am I worthy to serve
我够格
under Captain Jack Sparrow?
赫史杰克船长服务吗 ?
Or should I just kill you now?
还是我应该宣了你 ?
You're hired.
你被床佣了
Sorry. Old habits and all that.
抱娄 老习惯改不了
- Easy, sailor! - That's our captain you're threatening.
给我小心点 你冒犯了咱们的船长
- Time to go. - Aye!
该出发了 遵命
Thanks, mate. a
谢了 老兄
Carry on.
继续吧
Come on. then! Who wants some? a
来呀 谁想找死?
Form an orderly line and I'll have you all, one by one.
排好队 我一个一个解决
Come on. who's first? a
谁要先上?
James Norrington.
倪准将
What has the world done to you?
你怎么会沦落成这地步?
Heave!
用力
- Heave!
用力 !
Secure the mast tackle. Mr. Turner! a
杜先生 国定施索
Set to it!
动作快点
- Step aside. - Hey! Mind yourself!
让开 小心一点
Let go, boy!
放手 小子
No.
不
Haul that weevil to his feet.
把他绑起来
Five lashes will remind you to stay on 'em!
抽你五下你就会记住
- No! - Impeding me in my duties?
不要 你这个碍事的老家伙
- You'll share the punishment. - I'll take it all.
一样要受和无罚 我替他受胃
Will you, now?
是吗?
And what would prompt such an act of charity?
你为什么要对他这么好
My son.
我儿子
He's my son.
他是我儿子
What fortuitous circumstance be this?
这真是再好不过的巧合
Five lashes be owed. I believe it is. a
他要受五炎鞠刑
No. No, I won't!
我下不了手
The cat's out of the bag, Mr. Turner.
事实摆在眼前 老杜
Your issue will feel its sting, be it by the bosun's hand or your own.
如果你不亲手鞭打你儿子 我就让水手长动手
No.
不
- Bosun! - No!
水手长 不 !
You had it easy, boy!
算你幸运 臭小子
- Will. - [don't need your help.
我不需要你帮忙
The bosun prides himself on cleaving flesh from bone, with every swing.
你会被行刑长打得鞭鞭见胃
So I'm to understand what you dic was an act of compassion?
你算是帮了我大已了?
Yes.
没错
100 years before the mast, losing who you were, bit by bit,
在幽实飞船上待一百年 就会渐渐失去自我
until you end up... end up like poor Wyvern here.
直到你跟这老家人饮一样
Once you've sworn an oath to the Dutchman, there's no leaving it.
当你发了垢 血债不还清
Not until your debt is paid.
就永远不能离开
I've sworn no oath.
我并没有发誓
You must get away.
你一定要逃走
Not until I find this.
我要先找到这玩意
The key.
那把钥是
The dead man's chest.
聚魂棺
What clo you know of this?
你知道什么 ?
Open the chest with the key, and stab the heart...
用钥是打开聚魂棺刺死心脏
No, don't stab the heart. a
不 不能刺死心脏
The Dutchman needs a living heart or there'll be no captain,
幽实飞船需要活生生的心脏 不然就没有船长
and if there's no captain, there's no one to have the key.
没有船长 就拿不到钥是
So the captain has the key?
人铀是在船长手上?
- Where is the key? - Hidden.
人铀是在哪里? 功起来了
- Where is the chest?
聚魂棺在哪里?
Captain Sparrow!
史船长
Come to join me crew, lad? Welcome aboard.
小妞 你也来插一脚 ?
I'm here to find the man I love.
我来找我的心上人
I'm deeply flattered, son, but my first and only love is the sea.
多谢厚爱 但我爱的是大海
Meaning William Turner, Captain Sparrow.
我是说威廉 史船长
Elizabeth.
伊丽莎白?
Hicle the rum.
快把兰姆酒藏起来
These clothes do not flatter you. It should be a dress or nothing.
你干叫穿这么破的衣服 ? 不穿洋装干脆脱光光
- [happen to have no dress in my cabin. - Jack.
我的舱羽刚好没有洋装
I know Will came to find you. Where is he?
威尔来找你 他人呢 ?
Darling, l am truly unhappy to have to tell you this, but
亲爱的 我有坏消息
through unfortunate circumstances that had nothing whatsoever to do with me,
发生一连串意想不到的事 全都下我没关系
poor Will has been press-ganged into Davy Jones's crew.
威尔被迫成为深海阎王的船员
Davy Jones?
深海阎王 ?
Oh, please.
拜托
The captain of the Flying Dutchman?
幽衬飞船的船长?
- You look awful. What are you doing here? - You hired me.
你气色好差 你来干骂 ? 你请我来的
I can't help it if your standards are lax.
谁叫你标准那么佐
- You smell funny. - Jack!
你也全身发自
All l want is to find Will.
我只想找到威尔
Are you certain? Is that what you really want most?
你确定吗 你真的想找到他 ?
Of course.
当然
Because I would think you'd want to find a way to save Will most.
我以为你会想用最好的办法救他
- And you'd have a way of doing that? - Well. a
你有最好的办法? 嘿
- there is a chest. - Oh, dear. a
有一个箱子 又来了
A chest of unknown size and origin.
我不知道它的大小和来处
What contains the still-beating heart of Davy Jones.
里面是深海周王跳动的心脏
And whoever possesses that chest
只要拿到这个聚魂棺
possesses the leverage to command Jones to do whatever it is he or she wants. a
就能命令深海内王做任何事
including saving brave William from his grim fate.
包括拯救勇敢的威廉一条小命
You don't actually believe him, do you?
你不会真的相信他吧
How would we find it?
要怎么找到聚魂棺 ?
With this.
用这玩意
My compass is unique.
我的罗盘很特别
"Unique" here having the meaning of "broken."
意思是它坏掉了
True enough, this compass does not point north.
没错 这个罗盘不能指北
Where cles it point?
它指哪个方向?
It points to the thing you want most in this world.
它指你最想要得到的东西
- Are you telling the truth? - Every word, love.
你是说真的吗 ? 名如实言
And what you want most in this world
你最想要得到的东西
is to find the chest of Davy Jones, is it not?
就是深海阎王的聚魂棺对吧 ?
- To save Will. - By finding the chest of Davy Jones.
那就要找到深海交王的聚魂棺
- Mr. Gibbs! - Cap'n.
吉下先生 船长
- We have our heading. - Finally!
找到航向了 谢天谢地
Cast off those lines. Weigh anchor and crowd that canvas!
松开缆索 起错扬帆
Miss Swann.
史小姐
Welcome to the crew. a former commodore.
欢迎加入 前任准将
There's something to knowing the exact shape of the world and one’s place in it.
人人都该知道自己扮演的角色
l assure you, these are not necessary.
没有必要把我错起来
I thought you'd be interested in the whereabouts of your daughter.
我以为你想知道令千金的下落
- You have news of her? - Most recently seen on Tortuga,
你有她的消息? 有人在土图嘉港看到她
and then left in the company of a known pirate, Jack Sparrow,
跟秋名昭彰的海盗史杰克
and other fugitives from justice.
和一群唾弃正义的罪犯一起出海
"Justice"? Hardly.
正又?
Including the previous owner of this sword, I believe.
其中包括这把剑的前任主人
Our ships are in pursuit. Justice will be dispensed by cannonade and cutlass,
我们的舰队正在紧追不会
and all manner of remorseless pieces of metal.
他们会用威力强大的火炮 以及各种犀利的兵器伸张正义
I find it distasteful to even contemplate the horror facing all those on board.
想到那些罪犯会吃的苦头 我就觉得一阵反胃
What clo you want from me?
你想利用我哪一点?
Your authority as governor, your influence in London,
你身为总督对英王的影响力
and your loyalty to the East India Trading Company.
和你对东印度公司的患诚
To you, you mean.
你是说对你患心吧
Shall l remove these shackles?
你想脱看聊锋手错吗 ?
Do what you can for my daughter.
请你尽力救我女儿
So you see, Mercer, every man has a price he will willingly accept.
人人都愿意为某些东西付出代价
Even for what he hoped never to sell.
连舍不得的东西也得牺牲
I wager ten years.
我赌十年
I'll match ten years.
我跟十年
Agreed.
好
Wondering how it's played?
知道怎么玩吗 ?
- Lunderstand. - Liar!
我知道 你出老千
It's a game of deception. But your bet includes all the dice, not just your own.
这是吹牛的游戏 每个最子点数都算 不只是你的
- What are they wagering? - The only thing we have.
峙注是什么 ? 我们仅有的
Years of service.
待在船上的时间
- So any crew member can be challenged? - Aye. Anyone.
我可以跟任何人赌吗? 没错 任何人
I challenge Davy Jones.
那我要和深海交王峙一把
l accept, mate.
好 我跟你赌
- The stakes? - My soul. An eternity of servitude.
你拿什么当峙注 ? 我的灵魂 永远属于你
No!
不 !
Against?
你要什么 ?
- How clo you know of the key? - That's not part of the game, is it?
你怎么知道钥是的事 ? 这和这场财局无估
You can still walk away.
你可以退出
- What's this? - I'min. Matching his wager.
这算什么 ? 我赌的跟他一样
No! Don't do this.
别这样
The die is cast.
来不及了
I bid three twos.
我赌3个2点
It's your bid, Captain.
该你了
Four fours.
4个4点
Four fives.
4个5点
Six threes.
6个3点
Seven fives.
7个5点
Eight fives.
8个5点
Welcome to the crew. lad. a
你输定了
Twelve fives.
12个5点
Call me a liar, or up the bid.
不开患我就加注
And be called a liar myself for my trouble?
你在说谎 我在开吕
Bootstrap Bill, you're a liar and you will spend an eternity on this ship.
圣带比尔 你要永远留在船上
Master Turner. a feel free to go ashore
杜少黎 下一灵停靠港口时
the very next time we make port!
你就可以上岸了
Fool. Why did you do that?
你为什么这么傻?
I couldn't let you lose.
我不能让你输
It was never about winning or losing.
这根本就和输赢无估
The key.
那把钥是
You just wanted to know where it was.
你只想知道它在哪里?
Captain says I'm to relieve you.
船长叫我接你的班
Captain's orders.
船长的命令
Here. Take this. too. a
拿去 这也拿去
Now, get yourself to land, and stay there.
上了涯就不要回来
It was always in my blood to die at sea.
我天生注定要死在大海
It was not a fate l ever wanted for you.
我不希望你有同样的下场
It's not a fate you had to choose for yourself, either.
这不是你选择的命运
Aye. I could say I did what I had to, when I left you to go pirating.
我可以说我离开你 去当海盗是迫不得已的
But it would taste a lie to say it wasn't what I wanted.
不过老实说我是心甘情愿的
You owe me nothing, Will.
你没有欠我什么
Now go.
快走吧
They'll know you helped me.
他们会知道你救了我
What more can they do to me?
他们还能对我怎样 ?
I take this with a promise.
我要对你许下承诺
I'll find a way to sever Jones's hold on you,
我会用这把刀刺死他的心
and not rest until this blade pierces his heart.
把你从韶王手中救出来
I will not abandon you.
我不会去下你不管
I promise.
我向你保证
- Beckett? - Yes, they're signed.
贝克特? 已经签好了
Lord Cutler Beckett of the East India Trading Company.
上面签的是东印度公司贝克特
Will was working for Beckett and never said a word.
威尔赫贝克特做事却没有说
Beckett wants the compass. Only one reason for that.
贝克特要罗盘只有一个目的
Of course.
当然
- He wants the chest. - Yes, he did say something about a chest.
他想得到聚魂棺 他是提到过一个箱子
If the company controls the chest, they controls the sea.
拿到聚魂棺就能掌控大海
- A truly discomfiting notion, love. - And bad.
这真叫人不安 没好处
Bad for every mother's son what calls himself a pirate.
而有全对每一个海盗都没好处
I think there's a bit more speed to be coaxed from these sails.
我能让鬼盗船更快点
Brace the foreyard!
国定前桥
Might l enquire as to how you came by these?
你怎么拿到这些信
- Persuasion. - Friendly?
我说服他们 好言相功 ?
Decidedly not.
当然不是
Will strikes a deal, yet you were the one with the prize - full pardon.
威尔说话算话 信守承诺 你却说他们愿意赦免我
"Commission as a privateer on behalf of England
让我当大英帝国
"and the East India Trading Company.”
和东印度公司的私掠船船长
As if l could be bought for such a low price.
这么低的条件我才不答应
- Jack, the letters, give them back. - No.
把信还给我 不要
Persuade me.
那就来说服我
You do know Will taught me how to handle a sword?
威尔教我怎么用剑
As l said, persuade me.
我说过了 说服我
It's a curious thing.
真是耐人寻味
There was a time I would have wanted you to look like that while thinking about me.
我为了得到你对他的微笑 愿意付出一切
- [don't know what you mean. - [ think you do.
我不知道你在说什么 你清楚得很
Don't be absurd. I trust him. that's all. a
别俐了 我只是信任他
So you never wondered how your latest fiancé
你没想过威尔
ended up on the Flying Dutchman in the first place?
怎么会被抓到幽衬飞船呢 ?
Strange to come upon a longboat so far out in open water.
汪洋大海中怎么会有救生船 ?
Just put as many leagues behind us as you can. As fast as you can.
赶快离开刚才那地方
And what are we running from?
我们在躲什么 ?
That dress. Where did you get it?
那件婚纱哪里来的?
It was found aboard the ship.
在船上发现的
The crew thought it was a spirit bringing some omen of ill-fate.
船员认为是带来厄运的女鬼
- That's foolish. - Yes. Exceedingly foolish.
太荒唐了 荒唐到极点了
It brought good fortune. The spirit told us, "Pull in at Tortuga,”
女鬼叫我们到土图嘉港
and we made a nice bit of profit there.
结果赚了一大笔
Off the books, of course. a
当然是大饱私圳了
l imagine some of your crew may have jumped ship there.
我猜有些船员在那条船了
- Why do you ask? - Captain! A ship's been spotted.
你为什么这么问? 发现一盘船
- Colors? - She isn't flying any.
旗帜是什么颜色? 没有旗帜
- Pirates. - Or worse.
海盗般 或是更可怕的东西
You will watch this.
给我看清楚了
Let no joyful voice be heard!
让欢乐的声音消失
Let no man look up at the sky with hope.
人们不再了盼求希望
And let this day be cursed by we who ready to wake
证这一天被我们诅咒 准备
the kraken.
召唤海怪
No!
不
I've doomed us all.
我害惨了大家
It's the Flying Dutchman!
那是幽灵飞船
Mother Carey's chickens! What happened?
什么事搞得鸡飞狗跳
Must have hit a reef.
我们一定是撞到了礁石
Free the rudder! Hard to port then hard to starboard.
转向 和急堪转再急右转
- Free the rudder! - Hard to port!
快转向 和急左转
- Kraken!
海怪 ! 海怪 !
Here it is! Take it!
这里 拿去
Take it!
快拿去
The boy's not here. He must have been claimed by the sea.
那小子不在 一定被大海吞掉
lam the sea.
我就是大海
You need time alone with your thoughts.
你需要时间想一下
- Brig! - What of the survivors?
把他估起来 怎么处置生还者 ?
There are no survivors.
不准有生还者
The chest is no longer safe. Chart a course to Isla Cruces.
聚魂棺没有被偷的危险 设定航向前往十字岛
Get me there first. a or there'll be the devil to pay.
不抢先赶到 麻烦就大了
"First"?
抢先 ?
Who sent that thieving charlatan onto my ship?
谁把那小子带到船上
Who told him of the key?
是谁跟他说钥是的秘密的?
Jack Sparrow.
史杰克
My intuitive sense of the female creature informs me that you are troubled.
我对女性动物的知觉很敏锐 但觉得到你很烦恼
I just thought I'd be married by now.
我以为早就可以结婚了
I'm so ready to be married.
我好想嫁人
You know...
你知道
Lizzie, l am captain of a ship,
痢落 我是堂堂的大船长
and being captain of a ship, I could in fact perform a "marr-i-age” right here.
我身为船长可以主持一切 正式婚礼
Right on this deck.
就在这盘船的甲板上
Right now.
就是现在
No, thank you.
不 谢谢
Why not?
为什么 ?
We are very much alike, you and I. land you. Us.
咱们俩很像 我们是同一种人
Except for a sense of honor and decency and a moral center.
只是你没有良知和道德观念
And personal hygiene.
更没有卫生习惯
Trifles.
那是小事一桩
You will come over to my side. I know it.
跟我久了就会习惯
- You seem very certain. - One word, love. Curiosity.
你好像很自信 一个词形容你 好奇心
You long for freedom.
你渴望自由自在
You long to do what you want to do because you want it.
随心所和谷
To act on selfish impulse.
想做什么就做什么
You want to see what it's like.
你想要尝尝那种滋味
One day, you won't be able to resist.
总有一天 你会无法抗拒
Why doesn't your compass work?
你的罗盘为什么不管用?
My compass works fine.
我的罗盘很管用
Because you and I are alike,
你和我是同一种人
and there will come a moment when you have a chance to show it.
你总有一天会良心发现
- To do the right thing. - Llove those moments.
做出正确的决定 我喜欢正确的决定
l like to wave at them as they pass by.
更喜欢做出错误的决定
You'll have the chance to do something... something courageous.
你会有机会做英勇的事
And when you do, you'll discover something.
然后你会发现一件事
That you're a good man.
其实你是个大好人
All evidence to the contrary.
事实恰恰相反
I have faith in you.
我对你有信心
- Want to know why? - Do tell. dearie. a
你想知道原因吗 ? 尽管说吧
Curiosity.
好奇心
You're going to want it.
你对那种感觉很好奇
A chance to be admired and gain the rewards that follow.
受到章数和得到奖励的感觉
You won't be able to resist.
总有一天你会无法抗拒
You're going to want to know what it tastes like.
你一定要尝尝那种滋味
I do want to know what it tastes like.
我是想要尝尝那种滋味
But, seeing as you're a good man,
不过你还是好人
l know that you'd never put me in a position that would compromise my honor.
绝对不会逼我 人敌我不该做的事
I'm proud of you, Jack.
杰克 我以你为荣
Land. ho! a
陆地 !
Il want my jar of clirt.
我要那负泥土
- You're pulling too fast. - You're pulling too slow.
你划得太快了 你划得太慢了
- We don't want the kraken to catch us. - I'm saving me strength for when it comes.
会被海怪抓到 我要保持体力对付它
And I don't think it's "kracken” anyways. l always heard it said "krayken.”
而且他叫吴怪 不叫海怪
With a long a?
不是三声海吗 ?
No, no. no. no, no. no. no. "Krocken” ce is how it's pronounced in Scandinavian,
怪是北欧人原来的发音
and "kracken” is closer to that.
海怪是后来的说法
We ain't Scandinavians. are we? a "Krayken.”
我们又不是北欧人 是海怪才对
It's a mythological creature. I can calls it what I wants.
它是神话怪物 我怎么叫都行
Guard the boat. Mind the tide.
在船上留守
Don't touch my dirt.
别碰我的泥土
This doesn't work. And it certainly doesn't show you what you want most.
这不管用 它根本找不到东西
Yes, it does. You're sitting on it.
才怪 你就坐在上面
- Beg pardon? - Move.
什么 ? 让开
- "Guard the boat!” "Mind the tide!” - [could join the circus.
每炊都叫我们留守 我可以加入马戏团
Mind if l shine your shoes, sir?
搞不好还要我们替他探娃
They're here. And I cannot step foot on land again for near of a decade.
他们来了 而我十年内却不能踏上陆地
You'll trust us to act in your stead?
你放心我们动手吗 ?
I'll trust you to know what awaits you should you fail!
如果你们失败 就会死得很难看
- Down, then! a - Down!
沉下去 下沉
You actually were telling the truth.
你说的是实话
I do that quite a lot, yet people are always surprised.
当然了 你们总是不相信我
With good reason!
那是有原因的
You're all right! Thank God! I came to find you!
你没事 我来找你了
How did you get here?
你怎么来的?
Sea turtles. mate. a A pair of them, strapped to my feet.
海龟 一和脚绑一只
Not so easy, is it?
很不容易 是吧?
- But l do owe you thanks, Jack. - You do?
不过我倒要感谢你 是吗?
After you tricked me onto that ship to square your debt with Jones...
你骗我上幽买飞船替你还债…
- What?
什么 ?
..l was reunited with my father.
让我们父子团
Well, you're welcome, then.
不客气
Everything you said to me, every word was a lie!
你和我说的每一个字都是谎言
Pretty much.
差不多
Time and ticle, love. a
动作快点
Oi! What are you doing?
你在干六 ?
I'm going to kill Jones.
我要杀死深海周王
Can't let you do that, William.
我不准
‘Cause if Jones is dead. who's to call a his terrible beastie off the hunt. eh?
谁能阻止他召唤的海怪 ?
Now, if you please.
现在 麻烦你
The key.
把钥是给我
l keep the promises I make, Jack.
我要信守承诺
l intend to free my father. l hope you're here to see it.
希望你能亲眼目睹
I can't let you do that either. So sorry.
我也不能让你杀死他 抱娄
I knew you'd warm up to me eventually.
我就知道你会站在我这边
Lord Beckett desires the content of that chest.
贝克特要箱子里的东西
I deliver it, l get my life back.
我只要交给他就能取回一切
The dark sicle of ambition.
你终于露出那那恶的一面
I prefer to see it as the promise of redemption.
我倒是认为这是赎罪的机会
Stop it!
住手
- Guard the chest! - No!
不 !
This is barbaric! This is no way for grown men to...
这太野变了 你们都是大人
Fine! Let's just haul out our swords and start banging away at each other.
好吧 ! 那就拔出剑来杀个你死我活
That will solve everything! I've had it!
一切的问题都解决了 ! 我受够了 !
I've had it with wobbly-legged, rum-soaked pirates!
我受够你们这些海盗和酒鬼了
- How'd this go all screwy? - Well. each wants the chest for hisself. a
你们怎么会打成一团 他们都想把聚魂棺据为己有
Mr. Norrington, I think, is trying to regain a bit of honor,
侯先生想重抢苯严
old Jack's looking to trade it, save his own skin. a
杰克想换回自己一条命
then Turner, there, I think he's trying to settle some unresolved business
至于威尔
‘twixt him and his twice-cursed pirate father.
他想郁救那个 被诅咒两坎的海盗区和
- Sad. - This is madness!
真可怜 这太疯狂了
That chest must be worth more than a shiny penny.
那个箱子一定很值钱
Terrible temptation.
很大的诱惑
If we was any kind of decent, we'd remove temptation from their path.
我们是一对大好人 最好不要让他们受到这种诱惑
Enough!
够了
The heat!
我中时了
Bugger!
可恶
By your leave, Mr. Turner.
想我失隘了
Do excuse me while I kill the man who ruined my life.
我要宰了毁了我一生的家伙
- Be my guest. - Let us examine that claim for a moment.
请便 请听我一言 前准将
Who was it, that at the very moment you had a notorious pirate safely behind bars,
你把我这和名昭彰的海盗估起来
saw fit to free said pirate and take your dearly beloved all to hisself?
是谁把我放出来 然后抢走你心爱的未婚概 ?
So whose fault is it, really,
又是谁害你
that you've ended up a rum-pot deckhand what takes orders from pirates?
沦落成为听海盗命令的酒鬼 ?
Enough!
够了
Unfortunately, Mr. Turner, he's right!
威尔 他说得没错
Still rooting for you, mate.
我替你加油 老兄
We got it! We got it! We got it!
拿到手了 我们拿到手了
Hello, poppet.
小刀 你好
Come on. run! a
快点老瑞 快走
- Sword! - Sword! Sword!
剑! 剑! 剑
Follow my voice.
听我的指示
To the left... no, turn around. a
往左边 转过去
Go to the right.
到右边
No, that's a tree. a
那是一棵树
Shut it.
闭嘴
dar of dirt!
泥土
Right.
好吧
We've got it!
交给我们吧
Come on. Turner! a
来呀
Leave him lie! Unless you plan on using him to hit something with.
别管他 除非要用他挡剑
- We're not getting out of this. - Not with the chest.
我们死定了 拿聚驼棺准活不了
Into the boat.
快上船
- You're mad! - Don't wait for me.
你鸳了 不用等我
- lsay we respect his final wish. - Aye!
我们就遵照他的遗言吧 遵命
Your bravery is wasted.
你白扩了一场
I shall pry the chest away from your cold, dead hands.
我要把聚驼棺 从你冰冷的手上抢过来
Here you go!
拿去吧
Pirates!
臭海盗
- What happened to the chest? - Norrington took it to draw them off.
聚魂杞呢 ? 倪先生拿去引开他们了
- You're pulling too hare! - You ain't pulling hard enough!
你划得太快了 你划太慢了
- Where's the commodore? - Fell behind.
准将用 他没赶上来
My prayers be with him.
愿他安息
Best not wallow in our grief.
不过伤心也没有用
The bright side is you're back, and made it off free and clear.
至少你安然无意的回来了
Lord on high, deliver us.
主啊 救救我们
I'll handle this, mate. a
让我来搞定
Oi. fishface!
臭乌贼
Lose something? Eh? Scungilli!
章鱼怪 你在找什么 ?
Got it!
还在我手上
Come to negotiate, eh, have you, you slimy git?
你是来谈条件的吗 傻小子
Look what I got.
你看我有什么
! got a jar of dirt. {got a jar of dirt
我有一镀泥土 一匀泥土
And guess what's inside it?
你猜里面有什么
Enough!
够了
- Hard to starboard. - Hard to starboard!
和急右转
Brace up the foreyard!
国定前桥
Send his beloved Pear! back to the depths.
把鬼盗船炸沉到海底 开炮
She's on us! She's on us!
她来了 她下来了
- Let them taste the triple guns. - Aye, Captain.
让他们见识三管火炮的威力 遵命 船长
Make fast!
船首火斧
Go on, me darling! Show us what you've got!
绑紧点 让他们椎瞧你的厉害
Come on, girl!
加油
- She's falling behind! - Aye. We've got her!
她在后面 把她甩看了
- We're the faster? - Against the wind, the Dutchman beats us.
我们比较快 ? 逆风他们赢
- But with the wind... - We rob her advantage.
顺风咱们赢 我们上直了上风
Aye.
没错
We're out of range!
他们在射程以外
Break off pursuit, run her light and douse canvas!
别追了 把船饥拉下来
We're giving up. sir?
我们要放弃吗
They're giving up!
他们放弃了
My father is on that ship.
我和爸在那船上
We can take her. We should turn and fight.
我们比较快 可以打败他们
Why fight when you can negotiate? All one needs is the proper leverage.
可以谈条件 何必打仗呢 我们只要有筹码就没有问题
Where is it? Where is the thump-thump?
它在哪儿 尾脏哪儿去了
We must have hit a reef!
我们撞到礁石
No. It's not a reef! Get away from the rail!
不是矿石
- What is it? - The kraken.
那是什么 ? 海怪
- To arms! - Load guns! Defend the mast!
准备作战 子弹上膀
Itll attack the starboard. Run out the cannons and hold for my signal!
它会攻击右航 看我的指示开炮
Easy, boys!
小心点
Will?
威尔?
Steady! Steady.
稳着点
- Will! - Hold. Hold.
等一下
I think we've held fire long enough.
我们等太久了
- Will! - Fire!
威尔 ! 开炮 !
- It ll be back. We have to get off the ship. - There's no boats.
它会回来 我们要弃船 没有救生艇了
Pull the grates. Get all the gunpowder onto the net in the cargo hold!
拆掉铁敌门 把火药全部装进货舱的网袋
- Whatever you do, don't miss. - As soon as you're clear.
千万不要射焉了 你安全了我才开枪
We are short-stocked on gunpowder! Six barrels!
火药不够 只有六桶
Hurry up!
快点
- There's only six kegs of powder! - Then load the rum.
只剩六桶火药 把兰姆酒也装进去
Aye. the rum too!
好 兰姆酒
Step to!
快点
You coward.
你这和鬼玩意
Not good.
不好了
- Haul away! - Heave!
往后拉 用力
- Heave like you're being paid for it! - Put your backs into it!
用力 假装你们领薪水 使出你们吃奶的力气
- L got you! I got you! - Don't let me go!
我抓住你了 别放手
- lL won't let you go! - Shoot me!
我不会放手 救命啊
- Clear? - Higher! Higher!
让开 高一点
Come and get me. I'm over here!
来啊 来吃我啊
Come on!
快来啊
Shoot! Elizabeth, shoot! a
开枪 伊丽莎白 快开枪
Did we kill it?
杀死它了吗?
No. We just made it angry.
没 它更不爽了
We're not out of this yet. Captain, orders!
这下完了 船长 现在怎么办
Abandon ship. Into the longboat.
弃船 登上救生艇
Jack. The Pear!.
杰克 你要放弃鬼盗船?
She's only a ship, mate.
她只是一般船而已
He's right. We have to head for land.
没错 我们得划向陆地
- It's a lot of open water. - It's a lot of water.
这可是汪洋大海啊 很远
We have to try. We can get away as it takes down the Peari.
我们要试试看 趁海怪吞鬼盗船的时候逃走
Abandon ship.
弃船
Abandon ship or abandon hope.
不弃船必死无疑
Thank you, Jack.
谢谢你 杰克
We're not free yet, love.
咱们还没有脱身
You came back.
你回来了
l always knew you were a good man.
我一直都知道你是好人
Prepare to cast off. There's no time to lose.
快放绳子 别让费时间
Come on, Will. Step to!
快啊 威尔
It's after you, not the ship.
海怪要的是你 不是鬼盗船
It's not us.
也不是我们
This is the only way, don't you see?
你要牺牲小我 成全大我
I'm not sorry.
我并不后悔
Pirate.
你变成海盗了
Where's Jack?
杰克呢?
He elected to stay behind to give us a chance.
他留下来让我们逃生
Go!
快走吧
Bugger. Bugger. bugger.
可恶 可恶
Come on!
快点
Just got it. Come on.
就快好了 快点
Not so bad.
没那么臭吗
Hello, beastie. a
你好 畜牧
Jack Sparrow, our debt is settled.
史杰克 你的债还清了
The captain goes down with his ship.
船长和他的船一起沉入海底
Turns out not even Jack Sparrow can best the devil.
就连史杰克也无法打败那怪物
Open the chest.
打开聚魂棺
Open the chest. I need to see it!
快打开 我要看看里面
Damn you, Jack Sparrow!
去你的 史杰克
The last of our ships is returned.
最后一盘船回来了
Is there any news on the chest?
找到聚魂棺的下落吗?
None. But one of the ships did pick up a man adirift at sea.
没有 不过一盘船救了一个人
He had these.
他手上有这些信
I took the liberty of filling in my name.
我填上了自己的名字
If you intend to claim these, then you must have something to trade.
想要生效 你得拿东西换
Do you have the compass?
你拿到罗盘吗?
Better.
我有更好的东西
The heart of Davy Jones.
深海净王的心脏
Against the cold
这能清除寒冷
and the sorrow.
和悲伤
It's a shame.
真可异
I know you're thinking that with the Pear!
你有撮盗船
you could have captured the devil and set free your father's soul.
就能抓住恶魔 解放你父亲的有灵魂
Doesn't matter now.
已经来不及了
The Pear! is gone,
鬼资船沈入海底
along with its captain.
船长也死了
Aye.
是啊
And already the world seems a bit less bright.
这世界没他可不好玩了
He fooled us all right till the end,
他到死之前都在要我们
but I guess that honest streak finally won out.
我猜他最终良心发现
To Jack Sparrow.
数史杰克
- Never another like Captain Jack. - He was a gentleman of fortune, he was.
他是独一无二的史船长 也是一个唯利是图的绅士
He was a good man.
他是个好人
If there was anything could be done to bring him back...
如果我能够把他救活的话
- Elizabeth. - Would you clo it?
伊丽莎和白 你愿意吗 ?
What would you...
还有你
What would any of you be willing to do, hm?
你们都愿意吗 ?
Would you sail to the ends of the Earth and beyond
你们愿意航行到世界尽头
to fetch back witty Jack and him precious Pear!?
把史杰克和他的船带回来吗 ?
Yes.
我愿意
All right.
好吧
But if you go and brave the weird and haunted shores at world’s end. a
不过要到世界尽头 面对可怕的大海
then you will need a captain who knows those waters.
你们需要一个对世界尽头 非常熟悉的船长
So tell me. a what's become of my ship?
告诉我 我的船怎么了 ?